<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Allan Frankland</title>
    <link>https://AllanFrankland.github.io.git/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Allan Frankland</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 09:12:57 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://AllanFrankland.github.io.git/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Poetics I</title>
      <link>https://AllanFrankland.github.io.git/posts/poetics-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 09:12:57 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://AllanFrankland.github.io.git/posts/poetics-i/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;some-context&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  Some Context&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#some-context&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For Aristotle, the evolution of human culture is in large part the evolution of &lt;em&gt;technê&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We must point out that poetry, here, does not necessarily refer to what we today think of as literature in verse. The word used by Aristotle is ποιητής (pi.i’tis) which translates to &amp;lsquo;work&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;creation&amp;rsquo; - this word is used to describe all those products of language from verse to prose to lyric poetry and even treatises of philosophy and science.  For Aristotle mimetic works also include music and painting. I agree with Malcom Heath who defends his translation of &amp;lsquo;mimesis&amp;rsquo; to mean imitation rather than representation as&amp;ndash;he puts it&amp;ndash;the term representation fails to capture the subtle meaning behind Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s use of mimesis; the eagle is a symbol used to &lt;em&gt;represent&lt;/em&gt; Zeus, but it is by no means an imitation in the way that the statue on Olympia would have been. Representations then are wholly conventional whereas mimesis is much more concerned with a kind of accurate reflection and, as Aristotle says:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(Draft) On Thought-Terminating Clichés and the Left</title>
      <link>https://AllanFrankland.github.io.git/posts/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2025 11:37:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://AllanFrankland.github.io.git/posts/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The language of the totalist environment is characterized by&#xA;the thought-terminating cliche. The most far-reaching and complex&#xA;of human problems are compressed into brief, highly reductive,&#xA;definitive-sounding phrases, easily memorized and easily expressed.&#xA;These become the start and finish of any ideological analysis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Robert Lifton in his work &amp;lsquo;Thought Reform and the Psychology of Totalism: A Study of Brainwashing in China&amp;rsquo; coined the phrase &lt;em&gt;thought-terminating cliche&lt;/em&gt; to&#xA;define a phenomenon within Totalist ideologies that aim to reduce complex issues down to a memorable, reductive, yet decisive sounding phrase. Lifton refers to&#xA;Richard Weaver&amp;rsquo;s concept of &lt;em&gt;ultimate terms&lt;/em&gt; which represent either the ultimate good or the ultimate bad - these terms immediately signal an association of&#xA;ideas or thoughts with good and evil. To call something bourgeois is at once to tacitly call it evil and therefore, according to leftist Totalist doctrine,&#xA;unacceptable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
